（父亲的诅咒）
（悬赏通缉 杰克·斯派罗）
（赏金100英镑 不论死活）
（飞翔的荷兰人号）
爸爸？
Father?
亨利 你来干什么？
Henry, what have you done?
我说过会找到你
I said I'd find you.
看看我这样子
Look at me, son.
我不在乎
I don't care.
荷兰人号不是你该来的地方
There's no place for you on the Dutchman.
他们发现你了
They know you're here.
- 回去找你妈妈去 - 不
- Get home to your mother. - No!
快点儿走
Leave now!
趁现在还来得及
Before it's too late.
我不走 我不会罢休的
I won't! I'll never stop.
你就是把我扔下船 我肯定还会回来的
And if you throw me over, I'll come straight back.
我是被诅咒困在这里的
Don't you see I'm cursed to this ship?
这些我都知道
That's why I'm here.
我有办法打破你身上的诅咒
I think I know a way to break your curse.
让你离开荷兰人号
To free you from the Dutchman.
儿子 不行
Henry, no.
有一件神器
I've read about a treasure.
神器掌控着大海的一切神力
A treasure that holds all the power of the sea.
海神波塞冬的三叉戟可以救你
The Trident of Poseidon can break your curse.
儿子 三叉戟你是找不到的
Henry, the Trident can never be found.
我连你都找到了
I found you.
那是传说而己
It's just a tale.
就像你和杰克·斯派罗船长的传说
Like the tales of you and Captain Jack Sparrow?
杰克会帮我找到三叉戟
He will help me find the Trident.
不许去找杰克
You stay away from Jack.
永远别回大海
Leave the sea forever.
- 不能再这样像个… - 像个海盗？
- You have to stop acting like… - A pirate?
你拦不住我
I won't stop.
我只想要你回家
I want you to come home.
儿子
Henry…
对不起
I'm sorry.
你解除不了我的诅咒
But my curse will never be broken.
这是我的宿命
This is my fate.
你该知道放手
You must let me go.
我爱你 儿子
I love you, son.
杰克·斯派罗船长
Captain Jack Sparrow.
（九年后）
保持平衡
Keep even keel.
朝背风向靠拢
Haul in on the lee side!
快点儿推 你们这群舱底的耗子
Faster, you pathetic bilge rats!
赶紧给我把这里的水抽出去
You'll pump the bilge and fill the scuppers.
我们在全力追击海盗
We're chasing down pirates!
亨利 快点儿回来
Henry, get back here.
当心他们又把你赶下船
You don't wanna get kicked off another ship.
是一艘荷兰船
It's a Dutch barque.
兴许被海盗邦尼特给占了
Probably stolen by the Pirate Bonnet.
有麻烦了
My God.
你该知道擅离岗位的后果
I warned you of leaving your post, boy.
我要跟船长说句话
I need to speak with the captain.
- 你说什么？- 快让开
- What did you say? - Move!
亨利
Turner!
他们要进魔鬼三角区
She's going in, sir.
继续追
Chase her down.
不 不能追
No, don't do it.
不能再追了
Don't do it!
你没有权力跟船长说话 小子
You will not address the captain, boy.
船长 您看看地图
Sir, look at your charts.
再往前开就要把船开到魔鬼三角了
I believe you're sailing us into the Devil's Triangle.
你们听听 这新来的小子
You hear this, men? This landsman.
还真信那老掉牙的传说
believes an old sailor's myth.
船长 恕我直言
Sir, with all due respect,
我长年研究海洋的神话
I have spent my life studying the myths of the sea.
我知道所有的传说和诅咒
I know every legend and every curse.
船开进了魔鬼三角区的话
And I know ships that sail into the Triangle.
- 就很难再开出来了 - 抱歉 船长
- do not necessarily sail out… - I'm sorry, sir.
这个家伙显然是疯了
This one is clearly disturbed.
请相信我 船长 改变航向吧
Sir, trust in what I say. Change your course.
你敢命令我 臭小子？
You dare to give me orders, boy?
抓起来
Arrest him!
亨利
Turner!
不能让你害死一船人
I will not let you kill us all.
你这是叛变
This is treason.
不
No.
- 关起来 继续前进 - 不
- Lock him up. We're going in! - No!
固定右舷的转帆索
Belay that starboard brace.
拴紧绳索
Bind that line!
抓紧绳索
Stay to the chains!
这是最后一次饶你不死
This was your last chance, Turner.
要是我的话早把你吊死在桅杆上了
If it were up to me, I'd string you from the yardarm.
走吧
On deck.
舵手 稳住
Hold steady, helmsman!
杰克·斯派罗
Jack Sparrow.
他死了
He's dead.
埋在圣马丁岛上墓碑都没有
Buried in an unmarked grave on the Isle of Saint Martin.
（未知海域）
船长 水里有东西
Sir, there's something in the water.
右边有船
Ship to starboard!
那算不上是船 是船的残骸
That's no ship, sir. It's a shipwreck.
不
No.
它朝我们开过来了
She's sailing straight toward us.
开火
Open fire!
装弹 开炮
装弹
Reload!
守住甲板
Secure the deck!
你是谁？
What are you?
死人
Death.
（悬赏通缉 杰克·斯派罗）
杰克·斯派罗
Jack Sparrow.
嘘
Shh!
你认识他吗？
Do you know this pirate?
只听说过他
Only by name.
你在找他吗？
You're looking for him?
你在找他？
Is that a "yes"?
是的
Yes.
这么多年 我们被魔鬼三角区诅咒
For too many years, the Triangle has cursed us…
一直困在这人间地狱
condemned us to this hell on Earth.
逃离这里的关键 就是杰克·斯派罗
The key to our escape is Jack Sparrow…
还有他那该死的罗盘
and the compass which he holds.
不 不 不 不用害怕 孩子
No need to fear me, boy.
我一向会留下个活口作为见证
I always leave one man alive to tell the tale.
帮我去找到斯派罗
Find Sparrow for me…
带个话给他 就说船长萨拉查
and relay a message from Captain Salazar.
萨拉查
Salazar.
告诉他 我一定会重见天日
Tell him I will behold the daylight again.
到了那天
And on that day…
死亡
death…
会直接找上他的门
death will come straight for him.
能告诉他吗？
Would you say that to him?
求你了？
Please?
好的
Yes.
我想亲口告诉他 但是
I wish I could do it myself, but…
死人开不了口
dead men tell no tales.
《加勒比海盗5：死无对证》
（加勒比 圣马丁）
卡琳娜·史密斯 你无父无母 乃恶魔之女
Carina Smyth, you're an orphan born of the devil…
你被指控使用巫术
accused of practising witchcraft.
临死之前
Before you die…
你有什么需要坦白的吗？
do you have anything to confess?
我坦白 我不是一个女巫
I confess that I'm not a witch,
我只是相信科学而己
that I am a woman of science.
我坦白我独自生存下来
I confess that I have survived on my own…
靠的是我从未见过面的父亲的日记
with nothing but a diary from the father I never knew…
还有 对我身世的探寻
and a quest for the truth of who I am.
我坦白 我到死也不会放弃探寻真相
I confess that I will die before I give up the search.
我坦白
And I confess…
在我们谈话的时候 我把锁撬开了
that while we've been talking, I picked this lock.
今天 让我们庆祝
Today, we dedicate.
圣马丁皇家银行开业
the Royal Bank of Saint Martin.
这是我们加勒比海地区最安全的银行了
The most secure banking institution in the Caribbean.
新的金库 有5英寸厚
Our new vault is five inches thick…
重量超过了1吨
and weighs an imperial ton.
找到了 她在那儿
I've got her! I've got her!
抓住她
Get her!
别让她跑了 拦住那女巫
Don't let her get away! Stop that witch!
快点儿追 她在那儿 拦住那个女巫
Stop her! She's there! Get out of the way!
给我让开
Get out of my way!
有了这家银行
With this bank…
我们圣马丁城
the town of Saint Martin.
从此就迈入了现代化城市
enters the modern world.
- 很抱歉 长官 - 那女巫逃走了
- I'm so sorry, sir. - The witch escaped her chains.
给我把她抓回来 否则你们就代她去死
Find that wicked lass, or you'll swing in her place.
明白
Sir.
没有人 也没有军队
No man nor an army…
敢来抢我们圣马丁城的金库
can ever rob the gold from Saint Martin.
把金库打开
Open the vault.
是海盗
Pirate!
呃 海盗？
Pirates, eh?
海… 海盗
Pirate!
嗯
Hmm.
说起来还真是有点奇怪
This may seem a peculiar request…
不过你们有没有人知道
but could someone explain to me as.
我怎么在这儿？
to why I'm here?
斯克拉姆
Scrum.
还有多久？
How long?
再等等 我快想起来了
No, wait, it's coming to me.
让我稍微清醒一下
I need just a moment to clear me head.
全体就位
Make ready!
准备
Present!
别开火
Hold your fire!
金库里还有个女人
There's a woman with him in the vault!
你们不用管那个 荡妇
Never mind about that trollop.
市长 我觉得 那是您的夫人
Sir, I believe that's your wife.
怎么是你？
Frances?
哦 我想起来了
Right, I've got it.
想起来了 我在抢银行
I've got it! I'm robbing the bank!
- 杀了他 - 哦
- Shoot him! - Ooh!
快点儿
Come on!
拉
Pull!
再来
Come on!
原计划不是这样的
That was not part of the plan.
快追 别让他跑了
After him! Don't let him get away!
驾 快跑
Yo! Come on!
噢 噢
Oh, oh!
我不是去买了块羊肉嘛
Well, I got this mutton, didn't I?
哦 羊肉好贵的
Oh, that was too expensive.
（犬类禁入 女士止步）
（G·W·斯威夫特律师）
我的望远镜从来没让女人动过
No woman's ever handled my Herschel.
快让开
Clear a path!
不 不 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no!
停下 停下 停下
Stop! Stop! Stop!
快进来
Get inside!
向右急转
Hard to starboard.
先生
Sir.
你的天文定向不准
Your celestial fix was off.
我往北调了两度
I've adjusted two degrees North.
以后你的地图不会再有偏差了
Your map will no longer be imprecise.
不过你得从头画图了
Although you will have to start again with it.
你是女巫
You're a witch.
不 我不是女巫
No, I'm not.
我把两百颗恒星录入星表 就成女巫了吗？
Am I a witch for having catalogued over 200 stars?
女巫
Witch!
血月就要出现了
There is a blood moon coming.
我只是想买一个航海钟
I simply need to purchase a chronometer.
我出双倍价钱买这个
I'll pay you double for selling to a woman.
来人
Help!
有个女巫在我店里
There's a witch in my shop!
来人呐
Help!
快来人 我店里有女巫
Help! There's a witch in my shop!
还有个海盗
And a pirate!
我的店里有个女巫和海盗
There's a witch and a pirate in my shop!
你今天可真走运
Well, it's your lucky day!
那你们四个看到我的银行了吗？
Have either of the four of you seen my bank?
在那儿呢
Found it!
原计划里有你吗？
Were you part of the plan?
我不想惹麻烦
I'm not looking for trouble.
那你活着多没劲
What a horrible way to live.
别让女巫跑了 抓住她
Stop that witch! Get her!
跑不了了 要怎么办？
We're trapped. What do we do?
她在那儿 快
Yeah, there she is! Quickly!
你要尖叫一声
You need to scream.
那边 抓住那个女人
Over there! Secure that woman!
你卑鄙无耻
You filthy pirate!
我可没叫你骂我
No need for name-calling!
快点儿 驾
Come on, lads!
- 杰克 - 嗯？
- Jack! - Huh?
有桥？
Bridge?
白忙活了
It's empty!
那… 那钱呢？
Where is the dosh?
你们以为抢银行很容易？
Do you think that robbing a bank is easy?
现在一个子儿都没有
You gaggle of gutless heels of the womb's guilty…
还不是因为被你们这群唧唧歪歪的饭桶害的
of putting me in this dreadful pickle in the first place.
都排好队 照规矩上贡
Now line up and offer me your tribute.
你还找我们要钱？
You want us to pay you?
我不是这艘船的船长吗？
Am I not the captain of this ship?
就你这个 也叫船？
You call this a ship?
你说的宝藏呢？
Where's the treasure?
大家都快要饿死了
All of us are starving.
我们不会再跟着一个没有船的船长了
We will no longer follow a captain without a ship.
我有船
I have a ship.
我的黑珍珠号一直在身边
Black Pearl has never left me side.
- 现在巴波萨才是海上的霸主 - 嗯
- The pirate Barbossa rules these seas now. - Um.
他有十艘船 弹药充足
Has 10 ships, guns full.
更别提他的炮弹了
Not to mention his cannonballs.
听说一个有十八磅重呢
18 pounds each they say.
那瘸子的蛋蛋有那么重？
One-legged man with 18 pound balls?
难怪他走不动路
That's why he walks funny.
好了 伙计们
Oh, come, come, mates.
我们不是一起找到了马其顿的宝藏吗？
Did we not find the Treasure of Macedonia together?
那就是一堆烂木头
It was a troll of rotten wood.
- 迈达斯国王的金子 - 是一堆驴粪
- Gold of King Midas. - Pile of donkey dung.
认了吧 杰克
Face it, Jack.
你这是流年不利 霉运缠身
Bad luck dogs you day and night.
我运气好得很 你别乱说
Now that is a blatant fabrication.
你的好运到头了
You've lost your luck.
你的船也没了
You've lost your ship.
现在 你的船员也走了
Now, you've lost your crew.
杰克·斯派罗再也不是我们的船长了
Jack Sparrow is no longer our captain.
对不起 杰克
I'm sorry, Jack.
咱们俩算是走到尽头了
But we've reached the end of the horizon.
那好
Right then.
都走吧 对
You're all dismissed. Eh?
你们全都 被解雇了
All of ya, dismissed.
以后再也不能跟着杰克·斯派罗船长出海了
You'll never sail with Captain Jack Sparrow again,
知道吗
tell you that.
全城人都在谈论你
The whole town speaks of you.
君王号上唯一的幸存者
The only survivor of the Monarch.
你就靠一块浮木
A boy who paddled all the way to Saint Martin.
一路逆流而上划到了圣马丁
against the tide on a piece of driftwood.
发现你的时候 你念叨着海盗和三叉戟
Found jabbering about pirates and tridents.
长官 请您去掉这些镣铐
Please, sir, let me go of these chains.
我的职责是保卫这座岛和这片海域
My job is to protect this island and these waters.
而你的袖子 被撕掉了
And your sleeves have been ripped.
叛徒的标记
The mark of treason.
- 我们的船遭到了海盗的… - 那你就是临阵脱逃
- We were attacked by the dead… - You're a coward who ran from battle.
按逃兵处死
And that is how you'll die.
我相信你不是逃兵
I don't believe you're a coward.
请让我一个人待一会儿
Please leave me, sister.
我冒着生命危险来到这里
I've risked my life to come here,
是为了证实传言
to see if the rumours are true.
你知道三叉戟的事？
You speak of the Trident?
你是谁？
Who are you?
你为什么要找三叉戟？
Tell me why you seek the Trident.
三叉戟能破除一切海上诅咒
The Trident can break any curse at sea.
我的父亲就是被一道诅咒给困住的
My father is trapped by such a curse.
诅咒这种事根本没有科学依据
You're aware that curses are not supported by science.
可死人在说话
Neither are ghosts.
看来你确实疯了
So you have gone mad?
我真不该来这儿
I should never have come here.
那你为什么来？
Then why did you come here?
因为我是想要离开这座岛
Because I need to get off this island.
- 解读无人能… - 无人能懂的海图？
- To solve The Map No Man… - No Man Can Read.
海神波塞冬留下的海图？
Left by Poseidon himself.
你看过那个传说？
You've read the ancient text?
还看过所有的译本
In each language they were written.
不过没人见过那张海图 没人可以看得懂
But this map has never been seen nor read by any man.
别小瞧了女人
Luckily, I'm a woman.
这个 是伽利略的日记
This is the diary of Galileo Galilei.
他一生都在不停地寻找那个三叉戟
He spent his life searching for the Trident.
后来他发明了天文望远镜
It's why he invented the spyglass…
所以天文学家才总是盯着天空看
why astronomers have spent their lives staring into the sky.
你是说那无人能懂的海图
So you're saying The Map No Man Can Read.
是藏在星空里的？
is hidden in the stars?
这是父亲留给我的
It was left to me by my father.
他相信我能找到别人都找不到的东西
He believed I could find what no man has ever found.
我决不会让他失望的
and I will not let him down.
很快 就会出现血月
Soon there will be a blood moon.
只有到那时 我才能看懂海图
Only then can the map be read.
才能找到三叉戟
And the Trident found.
你是谁？
Who are you?
卡琳娜·史密斯
Carina Smyth.
想救你父亲就必须先救我
If you wish to save your father, you'll have to save me.
弄一艘船 我们去找三叉戟
Find us a ship and the Trident will be ours.
给我回来 女巫
Turn to me, witch.
站住
Hold.
他跑了
He's gone!
长官 他跑了
He's gone, sir!
去把逃兵抓回来
Find that coward.
把他和女巫一起吊死
He'll hang with the witch.
快走
Move out!
叫杰克船长去洗洗澡？
Think Captain Jack's washed up, eh?
我从来都不用洗澡
I've not had a wash in years.
搜查那条巷子
Check the alley down there.
你们两个 去教堂 其他人 跟我来
You two, check the church. The rest of you, with me.
噢 完了
Bugger.
（杰克·斯派罗 臭名昭著的海盗 赏金1英镑 不论死活）
能不能赏口酒喝？
May I please have a drink, please?
先把钱拿出来
Show me your silver.
要钱？
Silver?
做个交易吧？
How about a trade?
我要一瓶酒
Give me the bottle.
船长 这是怎么回事？
Capitán, what's happening?
杰克·斯派罗
Jack Sparrow.
杰克·斯派罗刚刚放弃了他的罗盘
Jack Sparrow has given away the compass.
阳光 阳光
Daylight. Daylight.
我们自由了
We are free!
好 好 该去找那个海盗了
Now, now. It's time to hunt a pirate.
海盗的人生
Pirate's life.
来吧 宝贝儿 噢
Come to daddy. Oh!
那家伙正是我们要找的
Just the man we've been looking for.
为什么？找我干什么？
Why? Why am I looked for?
通知全城 海盗杰克·斯派罗被抓到了
Let it be known that the pirate, Jack Sparrow,
天亮处决
will be executed at dawn.
处决我？
Executed?
我以后再也不来你们这儿了 长官
I will never set foot in this town again, sir.
我说到做到
You mark my words.
你死期到了 无赖
Dead now, you cur.
我是说真的
I do mean it, you know.
我保证再也不来你们这儿了
I shall never be back here again.
哈
Huh.
要释放海之神力
"To release the power of the sea…
则将一切分离
"all must divide."
是一座岛
It's an island.
星星指向一座岛
The stars lead to an island.
看这儿 长官
Look right here, sir.
很好 把其他几个关起来
Very good. Take the rest to the cells.
我要找一个海盗 杰克·斯派罗
I'm looking for a pirate. Jack Sparrow.
滚开
Bugger off.
跟你打听个人
Psst. I need to speak with you.
把你的剑给我
Hand me your sword.
我没有剑
I don't have a sword.
当兵的怎么会没有剑？
What kind of soldier has no weapons?
我因为叛逃被通缉
I'm currently wanted for treason.
看来你不是个好兵
So not the very good kind then.
我要找一个海盗 杰克·斯派罗船长
I'm looking for a pirate. Captain Jack Sparrow.
那你今天可真走运
Well, today is your lucky day.
因为我刚好就是你要找的那个船长 杰克·斯派罗
'Cause I just happen to be Captain Jack Sparrow.
不 不可能
No, it can't be.
我找了那么多年的… 就是你？
I've spent years searching for… this?
伟大的杰克·斯派罗 怎么会是一个坐牢的酒鬼？
The great Jack Sparrow is not some drunk in a cell.
你的船呢？船员呢？
Do you even have a ship? A crew?
裤子呢？
Pants?
伟大的海盗从不在意这些小细节
A great pirate does not require such intricacies.
你知道这一刻我等了多久吗？
Do you know how long I've been waiting for this moment?
我冒着生命危险混进来
The risks I've taken to be here.
你真的就是那个杰克·斯派罗？
Are you sure you're the Jack Sparrow?
最该问的是 你是谁？
Real question is, who are you?
我是亨利·特纳
My name is Henry Turner.
是威尔·特纳和伊丽莎白·斯万的儿子
Son of Will Turner and Elizabeth Swann.
呃
Ugh!
他们俩生了你这个坏小子？
You're the evil spawn of them two?
你妈妈是不是跟你提起过我？
Does mommy ever ask about me?
没有
No.
别不好意思
Oh, go on.
她梦里还叫我的名字吧？
She call my name in her sleep?
她没提起过你
She never spoke of you.
我们说的是那两个人吗？
Are you sure we're talking about the same people?
男的被诅咒
He's a cursed eunuch.
女的一头金发 很固执 噘着嘴
She's golden-haired, stubborn, pouty lips.
脖子像长颈鹿 还有一对丰满的…
Neck like a giraffe. And two of those wonderful…
是的 是的 就是她
Yes! Yes, it's her.
请你听我说 杰克 我现在只能指望你了
I need you to listen, Jack, because at the moment you're all I've got.
我知道怎么救我的父亲
I found a way to save my father.
有一件神器可以打破诅咒
There is one thing that can break his curse.
让他离开荷兰人号
and free him from the Dutchman.
海神波塞冬的三叉戟
The Trident of Poseidon.
啊 要找到这件宝贝
Ah. The treasure to be found.
得靠谁也看不懂的地图
with The Map That No Man Can Read.
从没听说过
Never heard of it.
这里还关着一个女孩儿 她有那张地图
There is a girl inside this prison, Jack, who holds that map.
月亮己经变红 三叉戟就要现世
The moon has turned to blood, the Trident will be found…
你将成为掌握大海的人
and you could be the one who holds the sea…
就像从前那样意气风发
and with it become all that you once were.
伟大的…
The great…
杰克
Jack!
真是对不起 你还在说啊？
I'm so sorry. Were you still talking?
我应该是睡着了
I believe I nodded off a bit.
还有一件事情
One more thing.
有个人让我把话带给你
A message from someone you know,
一个叫萨拉查的船长
named Captain Salazar.
我是认识一个西班牙人
I once knew a Spaniard named…
他有个西班牙名字
something in Spanish.
[西班牙语]
El Matador Del Mar.
海上屠夫
The Butcher of the Sea.
他？不 不
Him? No, no.
我跟你说 他死了 死得透透的
Quite happily, he's dead. Very, very dead.
- 船都沉了 - 就在魔鬼三角区
- Ship went down. - Inside the Triangle.
他要来找你
He's coming for you, Jack,
就像鬼故事里讲的那样 他要来复仇
to seek revenge as the dead man's tale is told.
我才不信呢
I don't believe you.
他都说什么了？
What did he say?
他说你的罗盘是他逃脱的关键
He said your compass was the key to his escape.
死人大军现在直奔你而来
An army of dead are coming straight for you, Jack.
海神波塞冬的三叉戟 是你唯一的希望
The Trident of Poseidon is your only hope.
我们达成共识了？
Do we have an accord?
我才不要进去跟他说
Well, I'm not going in there to tell him.
不是你要说的吗？
It was your idea.
不 我是说 你去跟他说
No, it was my idea for you to tell him.
可是你比较讨他喜欢
He likes you more than me.
他谁都不喜欢
He doesn't like anybody.
抱歉 船长
Sorry, sir.
我们知道您说过绝对不能打扰您
We know you said never to disturb you.
没事不能随便进来
Or to come in without good cause.
就算有事也要先 呃
Or to speak without first, um…
要先问问自己…
Asking ourselves…
问问自己 这事是不是真的有必要报告给您
Whether our thoughts were absolutely necessary.
就像船着火那次
Like the time the ship was on fire.
那就是个有必要报告的事情
That being an example of necessary thought.
船长 我们再次道歉 为 为 为了那次大火道歉
Sir, again, we do apologise for starting that fire.
什么事？
Speak.
是您的船 船长
It's your ships, sir.
接连遭袭击 但是对方不为钱财
They're being attacked by an enemy that takes no riches.
没错 平白无故地杀人
Kills without provocation.
我的船？
My ships?
这不可能
Not possible.
有三艘己经沉了 船长
Three have already been sunk, sir.
听说对方的船长叫萨拉曼德
They've been sunk by a captain called Salamander.
萨马瓦尔
Samovar.
萨拉查？
Salazar.
就是萨拉查 船长
That's it, your sirness.
每次他都留下一个活口 帮他传话
He leaves one man from each vessel to tell the tale.
我们的船一艘一艘地沉了
The entire fleet is being sunk…
我们就快要… 要死了
and we'll soon be dead.
可能我们也要失业了
And quite possibly out of business.
我要跟你们的女巫谈一谈
I'll be needing some time with your witch.
我己经恭候多时了 船长
I've been expecting you, Captain.
想要喝一杯茶吗？
Perhaps you'd like some tea?
茶就不必了 你太客气了
I shall pass. Thank ye kindly.
进我的门要付出血的代价 船长
The price of crossing my door is blood, Captain.
怪不得我看你这儿的生意也不怎么样
That explains why you're not so busy.
每笔账我都收回来了
Everyone pays eventually.
珊萨 我们过去是有协定的
Shansa, you and I made a bond long ago.
我把你从纹刑架上救下来 记得吗？
I saved you from the gallows, remember?
我帮你诅咒了敌人
And I cursed your enemies.
现在你又怕了 又来找我
But now you come to me in fear,
因为死人己经掌控了整个海面
as the dead have taken command of the sea.
那些死人为什么找上我？
And what would the dead be wanting with me?
不是找你 船长
Not you, Captain.
他们要找一只麻雀
They're searching for a Sparrow.
杰克？
Jack?
杰克要去寻找三叉戟
Jack will sail for the Trident…
带着女孩和珍珠
with a girl and a Pearl.
那三叉戟 没有人能找得到
The Trident can never be found.
三叉戟是杰克唯一的希望
The Trident is Jack's only hope.
死人大军虽然在海上无敌 却无法上岸
The dead are conquering the sea, unable to step on dry land.
不如你远离大海 去乡下养老
Maybe you should retire to the countryside.
你要我去乡下？开牧场？
You mean grass? On a farm?
挤牛奶 做奶酪是吗？
Milkin' a cow, makin' cheese,
那我的财宝怎么办？
while they sink my treasure?
那得问你自己 船长
Ask yourself this, Captain.
那是值得你舍命守护的宝贝吗？
Is this a treasure worth dying for?
我是个海盗
I'm a pirate.
一辈子都是
Always will be.
我要怎样才能守住我的东西？
So how do I save what be mine?
杰克有一个罗盘
Jack held a compass.
能够指引你找到你最渴望的东西
which points you to the thing you desire most.
但若背弃罗盘
But betray the compass,
它将释放你最深的恐惧
and it releases your greatest fear.
海盗最惧怕的就是萨拉查 是不是？
A pirate's greatest fear be Salazar, is it?
怎么在你手上？
How did you get this?
我自有办法
I have my ways.
带他们去 别等杰克找到三叉戟
Lead them to Jack before he finds the Trident…
你所有的宝贝 就会回到你手里
and all your treasure will come back to you.
看来要跟死人做个交易了
Time to make a deal with the dead.
快点 别磨蹭
Come on, pirate!
等等 停下
Hold on. Stop!
老爸？
Dad?
杰克大叔
Uncle Jack!
杰克小子 最近好吗？
Jackie boy! How's it going?
没什么可抱怨的 你呢？
Can't complain really. You?
我这一上午就等一顿打
I've been waitin' all morning in here for a beating.
这儿的服务太差了
But the service is terrible.
差得不行
Shameful.
杰克
Jack.
海水己被血染红
The oceans have turned to blood.
你最好待在陆地上 更安全
Best to stay on dry land where it's safe.
我马上就要死在陆地上了
I'm about to be executed on dry land.
好主意
Good point.
我跟你讲过骷髅的笑话吗？
Did I ever tell you the one about the skeleton?
- 讲过很多次 - 一个骷髅来到酒吧
- Yes, you have. Many times, in fact. - Skeleton goes into a bar…
要了杯啤酒和拖把
orders a beer and a mop.
还是很好笑
Funny as ever.
够了 该走了
Come on, let's go.
哦 他们要是掏你肠子
Oh, if they disembowel you,
叫维克托来干
ask for Victor.
他下手最轻了
He's got the softest hands.
- 谢谢 - 报我的名字
- Thank you! - And mention my name.
还能保住你的脚
They won't cut your feet off.
出来 你是第一个
Come on. You're up first.
你想怎么死啊 海盗？
And how would you like to die, pirate?
纹刑？枪决？还是最新发明的断头台？
Hanging, firing squad, or a new invention: the guillotine.
断头台？是法国的？
Guillotine? Sounds French.
我喜欢法国货 你知道吗？他们发明了蛋黄酱
I love the French. Did you know that they invented mayonnaise?
坏不到哪儿去 是法国的吧？
How bad could it be? It's French, eh?
噢 是这样的？
Oh, well, then.
啊 我改主意了
I've changed me mind!
我说 求你们了 呃 我胆子小 我会吓尿的
No, please! Have mercy upon me! I'm a bed-wetter.
噢 不是吧 砍个头还要爬这么高吗？
Oh, come on. I mean, I have to walk upstairs as well for this?
把篮子拿来
Bring the basket.
要篮子干嘛？
Basket? Why?
吊死她
Strap him down!
要不这样吧 听我说
Here's an idea. Here's an idea.
我 我们用老办法 砸石头好吗？
Why don't we try a good old-fashioned stoning, eh?
我现在就想被石头砸
I'd kill to be stoned right now.
大家也能参与进来 是吧？
Gets the crowd involved, doesn't it?
我要见掏肠子的维克托
I should like to speak to Victor in Disembowelment.
我要见你们的…
I should like to speak to…
我 我不是个爱抱怨的人
I'm not one to complain normally,
不过这个篮子都满了
but this basket's full of heads.
卡琳娜·史密斯有遗言
The final words of Carina Smyth.
安静
Quiet!
卡琳娜·史密斯有话要说
The final words of Carina Smyth.
听着 我不是女巫
Good sirs, I'm not a witch…
但是我原谅你们的愚昧和无知
but I forgive your common dimwittedness and feeble brains.
也就是说 你们大多都是猪脑子
In short, most of you have the mind of a goat.
抱歉长官
Pardon me, sir.
即将被处决的人一般是没有机会
Is it not common practice for those about to be executed…
说遗言的吧？我也不是很清楚…
to be granted a last, I don't know, something…
我在发表一个重要的观点 请你耐心一点
I believe I was making a point. If you could just be patient.
不行
No!
我的脑袋就要被砍下来了 情况紧急
My head's about to be lopped off, hence the urgency.
我的脖子也快要断了
And my neck is to be broken.
你知道吗？某些情况下 脖子是不会断的
Did you know that on occasion, the neck doesn't actually break?
只是… 很疼
It just hurts.
- 什么？- 是真的
- What? - Oh, yes.
有人吊了好几个小时 眼珠外凸舌头肿大
I've seen men swing for hours, eyes bulging, tongues swelling…
- 发出恶心的咯咯声 - 能让我先说吗
- revolting gurgling sound. - May I finish?
不 你太走运了
No! You're lucky.
我也想被吊死
Wish I was hung.
- 先把海盗杀了吧 我等着 - 女巫优先
- Kill the filthy pirate. I'll wait. - But witches first.
我不是女巫 你没听我说吗？
I'm not a witch. Were you not listening?
我真是个猪脑子 听不懂
Quite hard to listen when you have the mind of a goat.
够了 都杀掉
Enough! Kill them both!
再拿个绳子来
Get another noose!
就凭你 想打败我们 小子？
Did you think you could defeat us, boy?
当然不是
No, sir.
我只是来转移视线的
I'm just the diversion.
开火
Fire!
赶紧用石头砸我吧
Still rather be stoned!
装弹药
Reload!
啊
Ugh!
谢谢
Thank you.
死吧
Die!
过来 该死的海盗
Come here, you pirate scum!
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey!
噢 不
Oh, no.
你要干什么？不 不…
What are you doing? No, no, no!
小心
Careful!
马来了？
Horses?
噢
Oh!
谢谢了
Thank you!
不客气 小姐
You're welcome, me lady.
接住你了
Got you!
就知道你们这帮叛徒会回来
Knew you'd come crawling back, traitor.
是特纳家的小子 出了十个银币保你的脑袋
The Turner boy gave us 10 silver pieces to save your neck.
从现在开始起我们就是盟友了
From this moment on, we are to be allies.
你这样不怀好意地抱着我 我们怎么当盟友？
Considering where your left hand is, I'd say we're more than that.
能向我保证带我去找三叉戟吗？
We find the Trident together. Do I have your word?
我向你保证把你的手剁掉
You're holding everything but my word.
那我就赐予你们救我的荣幸 但要给点儿钱
Then I bestow upon you the honour of saving me for a small donation.
你指望我们救你 还给你钱？
You expect us to pay you to save you?
是的
Yes.
只要十个银币
For a mere 10 pieces.
你想得美
Madness!
我们最多给你五个
We won't pay more than five!
好吧 那就八个
Well, then… Eight it is.
没工夫跟你开玩笑 我现在快抱不住你的左舷了
Perhaps we could discuss this later as I'm having trouble hoisting your port!
那不是左舷 那是船尾
You are far from port. That is my stern.
你确定？
Are you sure?
当然确定
Positive.
哦 瞧瞧
Well, look at this.
我只要杀了逃兵 女巫就吊死了
If I kill the coward, the witch hangs.
这可是一举两得啊
Two for the price of one.
你可千万别放手
Please don't let go of me.
他要杀了我 我就得放手了
Might be difficult once he kills me.
先生们 这两个犯人能带我们找到三叉戟
Gentlemen, these two prisoners will lead us to the Trident.
船长
Captain.
你真觉得我们能找到三叉戟吗？
Do you really think we can find the Trident?
吉布斯总管 别瞎操心了
Master Gibbs, you old worrywart,
根本没什么可担心的
there's nothing to be concerned about at all.
能出什么问题呢 你说呢？
What could possibly go wrong, eh?
这就是你的计划？落到海盗手里被折磨死
So this was your plan? To be tortured and killed by pirates.
是你让我找一艘船的
You said you needed a ship.
这也叫船？
You call this a ship?
砍了它
Cut the shard!
做好淹死的打算
Prepare to drown!
我亲爱的船员们 今天终于…
Me dear beloved crew, finally, today is…
（垂死海鸥号）
出了点问题
Something's gone wrong.
没沉
She floats!
正前方有船
Ship dead ahead!
船长
Sir.
我们绝不是要质疑您的决策和判断 不过…
We would never question your reason as a captain but…
不过 是什么原因
But is there a reason…
让船长您 往这个不太合适的方向前进？
as captain, you've chosen to sail in this unreasonable direction?
即将有人登上我们的船
Tell the men to prepare to be boarded…
大家各就各位 不许害怕
to stand their ground and show no fear.
船长 那艘船朝我们过来了
Capitán, a ship sails toward us.
萨拉查船长
Capitán Salazar…
我听说你在找杰克·斯派罗
I hear you be looking for Jack Sparrow.
都别动
Hold point!
给我原地待命
And await orders.
我就是船长巴波萨
My name is Captain Barbossa,
我站在您面前 怀着真心诚意
and I stand before you with cordial intent.
怀着真心诚意？
Cordial intent.
都听到了吗？这个海盗跟我提诚意
Do you hear that? This pirate wishes to be cordial.
那我也让你见识一下我的诚意 伙计
So let me show you what my cordiality is, hombre.
我的剑敲一下 你的人就会死一个
Every time I tap my sword, one of your men will die.
所以有话快说
So I suggest that you speak quickly.
有什么话还是赶紧说吧
Might want to go a bit faster, Capitán.
杰克·斯派罗在哪儿？
Where's Jack Sparrow?
杰克去海里找三叉戟了
Jack be sailing for the Trident.
不 那是死人的世界
No, the sea belongs to the dead.
三叉戟能掌控大海
The Trident controls the sea.
不 不
No! No!
没有这种东西
There's no treasure.
无论什么宝贝也救不了他 他死定了 你也是
There's no treasure that can save him. He will die, as will you.
只有我才能带你找到他
I be the only one that can lead you to him.
我保证你明天日出之前就能要了杰克的命
I declare you shall have Jack's life by sunrise on the morrow…
否则 你就要我的命
or you can take me own then.
这样你同意吗？
Do we have an accord?
带我去找他 我就让你还能说话
Take me to him, and you will live to tell the tale.
我向你保证
You have my word.
多谢您 不杀我的船员
I thank ye on behalf of me crew.
好吧 你就带着剩下的人
Well, hey, you can take what's left of them.
活人跟我们结盟了
The living come aboard!
好吧 伙计们
Right, gentlemen.
卡琳娜 我们时间不多了 那些死人马上就追过来了
Carina, we haven't got much time. The dead are sailing straight for us.
真的假的？
Is that so?
真的 死人跟我说的
Yes, I've spoken to them.
死人跟你说的？
You've spoken to them?
那海妖和人鱼也跟你说过话吧？
Have you spoken to krakens and mermaids as well?
谁都知道海妖不会说话
Krakens don't speak. Everyone knows that.
我当然知道 我就不该救你
Of course. I never should have saved you.
和你说的一样 昨天晚上月亮变红了
Last night, there was a blood moon, just as you described.
告诉我你发现了什么？
Tell me what it revealed.
我凭什么相信你？
And why should I trust you?
你都让我抱你的左舷了 记得吗？
You trusted me to hold your port, remember?
那是船尾 你显然没有什么航海经验
It was my stern. Clearly, you need to spend more time at sea.
告诉我你发现什么了 我保证可以帮你
Tell me what you found and I promise to help you.
我不需要帮助
I don't need any help.
那你当初找我干什么？
Then why did you come to me, Carina?
为什么我们在这儿一起出海寻找同一件宝物？
Why are we tied together in the middle of the sea, chasing the same treasure?
血月显示一条线索
The moon revealed a clue.
「要释放海之神力 则将一切分离」
"To release the power of the sea, all must divide."
分离？什么意思？
Divide? What does it mean?
我还不确定
I'm not sure yet.
我们会弄明白的
Then we'll find out.
这里面根本没有海图
There is no map in this map.
把日记还给我
Give me my diary.
把「无人能懂的海图」给我
Give me The Map No Man Can Read.
要是你能看懂 就不叫「无人能懂的海图」了
If you could read it, then it wouldn't be called "The Map No Man Can Read."
拜托别说了 你说不过她的
I beg you, please, don't argue with her.
这船上大多数人都不识字
Most of the men on this ship can't read.
所以所有的海图都是… 无人能懂的海图
Which makes all maps The Maps That No Man Can Read.
要是你看不懂 那它就没用了 我也是
Well, if you can't read it, then you have no use for it or me.
再说一遍
Let me start again.
把那个海图给我
Show me the map.
我给不了 它还没出现呢
I can't. It doesn't yet exist.
她是个女巫
She's a witch!
我是天文学家
I'm an astronomer.
啊 啊 她是研究蚊子的
Ah! Ah, she breeds donkeys.
什么？不是 天文学家是研究天空的
What? No. An astronomer contemplates the sky.
- 对呀 蚊子就在天上飞 - 不是 跟蚊子没关系
- Yeah, on a donkey? - No! There's no donkey!
问一下 你怎么繁殖它们？
Well, then how do you breed them?
让我把问题变简单一点
Allow me to simplify this equation.
你把海图给我
Give me the map…
不然我就…
or I will kill…
杀他 我就杀了他
him. I'll kill him.
你杀吧
Go on then.
你在吓唬人
You're bluffing.
你的脸红了
And you're blushing.
把那个小子扔下去
Throw him over.
来吧 快
Come. Come on.
- 来吧 - 快点 快
- Come on. - Come on. Come on.
我们管这叫「拖龙骨」
We call this keelhauling.
小亨利会被扔下船
Young Henry will be tossed over…
然后被拖到船的底部
and he will be dragged under the ship.
好啊 你们还等什么？
All right. What're you waiting for?
呃 他不像是在吓唬…
Uh, he doesn't appear to be…
- 闭嘴 闭嘴 - 不 我不是吓唬你
- Zip, zip. - Nope, not bluffing, me.
他好像有话要说
He's trying to say something.
不 不 船上没吃的 抱歉
No, no, we don't have any food aboard. Sorry.
他要是淹死了算运气好的 免得被藤壶活活刮死
If he's lucky, he'll drown before the barnacles shred him to ribbons.
藤壶？
Barnacles?
就像一千把小刀在刮你的背
Like a thousand knives across your back.
当然 血还会引来鲨鱼
'Course the blood attracts sharks.
鲨鱼？
Sharks?
船头有鲨鱼
Shark off the bow!
要我说 现在会游泳都救不了他的小命了
I would say that swimming is no longer his primary concern.
海图在那儿
The map is there!
哪儿？
Where?
在你手指尖儿上？
On the tip of your finger?
不 在天上
No. In the heavens.
日记能帮我找到藏在星空里的海图
That diary will lead me to a map hidden in the stars.
拉他上来 我今晚就能找到海图
Let him up. I'll find it tonight.
晚了 来不及了 你自己去看
Sorry, can't bring him up. Look for yourself.
我就说嘛 脸红啦
As I said… blushing.
该死的海盗
Filthy pirate.
大海己被血染红
The sea has turned to blood.
一个水手被冲上岸说着什么三叉戟
A sailor washed ashore talking about the Trident.
他还要找杰克·斯派罗
He was looking for Jack Sparrow.
而那个海盗救走了纹刑架上的女巫
The same pirate who saved a witch from the gallows.
她不是女巫
She's no witch.
可你是
But you are.
而且你一定会帮我们
And you're going to help us.
你害怕了 上尉
You're afraid, Lieutenant.
船在夜色中燃烧 你想知道能否保护自 己
As ships burn in the night, you want to know if you can save your own.
想知道三叉戟是否真实
If the Trident is real.
为我解读那面墙上的信息 不然就杀了你
You're going to read that wall for me or you will die.
大英帝国要得到三叉戟 统治海洋
The British Empire will have the Trident and rule the sea.
告诉我那海盗要跟着女巫去哪儿？
I want to know where that pirate is going with that witch.
你的命运在这些星星之中
Your destiny is in these stars.
我将为你指路
I will set your course.
哦 面条吃人啦
Spaghetti wolf!
早知道是这样我何必找你？
Why did I bother coming to you?
死人在追杀我们而你坐着等死
The dead are hunting us down and you do nothing.
等死？我哪儿像等死的？
Nothing! You call this nothing?
你就知道喝酒 还睡大觉
You're drunk! And you're sleeping.
你说得不错 小子 我一下儿就做了两件事
My point exactly! I am doing two things at once.
有些人本来就没得救 对吗？
You can't save the unsaveable, mate.
我不管 反正你一定要帮我
Like it or not, Jack, you're going to help me.
破除我父亲身上的诅咒
I will break my father's curse.
下次你要举剑 小子 最好有胜算
Next time you raise a sword, boy, be the last to die.
噢
Oh.
让我教你一招 哄姑娘嘴巴要甜
Might I suggest you entice her with a bit of flattery?
我只想救的我父亲 没别的
I'm here for my father, nothing more.
我明白 你肯定是爱上她了
I knew it. Absolutely smitten with her.
那你一定要小心 如果要追棕发女孩
Now, a bit of discretion when courting a brunette…
千万别追她的姐姐
never pursue her sister.
但是 如果你没法抗拒她姐姐的魅力
But if you cannot avoid the charm of her sister…
就杀了她哥哥
kill the brother.
明白吗？
Savvy?
不 我不明白
No, I do not savvy.
谁伤过你的心？
Who hurt you?
哦 对了 既然你听了我的忠告 你就要付我五个银币
By the way, that little sliver of knowledge will cost you five pieces.
我才不会付你钱呢
I'm not paying you for that.
这话跟女人可说不得
Never say that to a woman.
有些东西你看不见 并不代表它不存在
Just because you can't see something, doesn't mean it's not there.
比如海图？
Like the map?
我必须找到它
I have to find it.
那样我才能知道我是谁 我父亲是谁
It's the only link to who I am. Who my father was.
看来我们都是一心想要找回父亲
So we've both spent our lives searching for our fathers.
或许你和我就是同一类人
Perhaps you and I are closer than you think.
出太阳了 你的时间到了
The sun is up, and so is your time.
我不是要否认 但太阳完全升起 协议才算到期
Not to disagree, but the precision of our accord ends at sunrise.
这只是一束光 离太阳完全升起还早着呢
This be but first light, far from a fully risin' sun.
我知道您是个讲信用的人
And I know you to be a man of honour.
信用？你还不了解我
Honour? You know nothing of me.
我知道被杰克打败的滋味
I know what it's like to be bested by Jack Sparrow.
他是我们共同的敌人
He's an enemy to us…
你又不知道我是谁
You don't know who I am.
我 我听说过一个强大的西班牙船长
I've heard stories of a mighty Spanish captain,
他是海上屠夫
El Matador Del Mar.
他令人闻风丧胆 因为他追杀了上千人
A man who scourged the sea, hunted and killed thousands of men.
不不不 不是普通人 不不
No, no, no. Men, no. No, no, no.
是海盗 啊？
Pirates, eh?
是海盗
Pirates.
海盗像病菌一样在海上世代繁衍
Pirates had infected the seas for generations.
害得我父亲和我祖父丢了性命
Taking the life of my father and his father before.
所以我发誓要彻底结束这场瘟疫
So I vowed to end this plague once and for all.
我说到做到 摧毁了数十艘海盗船
And that is what I did. I destroyed dozens of ships.
最后几艘船联起手来 妄图要打败我
The last ones joined together to try and defeat me!
他们很快就明白 一切都是徒劳
But they soon realised it was hopeless.
什么也抵挡不住沉默玛丽号
Nothing could stop the Silent Mary.
把它们都给我击沉 快点儿 快点儿
Hit them below the water line. Vamos! Vamos!
坚持住
Hang on, boys!
大海终于恢复了… 平静
The sea was finally pure.
海面上再也没有碍眼的骷髅旗
Their wretched flags would no longer stain the sea.
他们求您宽恕
They are begging for mercy.
宽恕？宽恕？
Mercy? Mercy?
没有宽恕
There's no mercy.
子弹上膛
Make ready!
帮帮我们
Please, help us!
再见吧
Adiós!
开火
Fire!
现在要靠你了 杰克
It's up to you now, Jack.
这个罗盘 能指出你心中的愿望
This compass points towards what you want most.
永远 别背叛它
Never betray it.
是魔鬼三角区
The Devil's Triangle.
我就这么看着几艘海盗船滚滚的浓烟
The last of their ships were burning before my eyes.
就算我享受着… 胜利
And in that moment of victory…
我听到了他的声音
it's when I heard it.
嘿 等一下 船长
Hey! Hold on, Capitán.
一艘船冲出了浓烟想要逃跑
One ship was trying to escape through the smoke.
多好的天气 出发吧
It's a lovely day for a sail, innit?
在那儿 在瞭望台上有一个
And there, in the crow's nest…
年纪很小的海盗
there was this young pirate boy.
在我看来就剩下你和我了
The way I see it, there's just the two of us left.
现在投降我就饶你一命 很简单
You surrender to me now and I'll let you live. Simple.
他站在那儿 就像一只小麻雀
He stood there looking like a little bird, eh?
从那天起
And from that day…
他的名字让我恨到了骨子里 一辈子都忘不了
he earned himself a name that would haunt me for the rest of my days…
杰克·斯派罗
Jack the Sparrow.
怎么样？你现在向我投降 我就放过你
Right then. You surrender to me now and I let you live.
我保证饶你一命
I shall let you live.
这小子 这小子竟敢如此藐视我的实力
This boy… This boy was mocking my power,
于是我追了上去
so I chased him…
我一定要亲手割开他的喉咙
knowing that I would run my knife along his neck…
他死了 我就杀尽了所有海盗
and when he was dead, I would finish finally with the pirate's life.
跟上他们
Follow him in.
（邪恶神女号）
去纹架那边 拿些绳子来
To the gallows. Grab some lines.
准备急转 向左转
Prepare the bootleg. Portside.
现在扔
Throw it now.
急转掉头
Bootleg turn.
这是干什么？
What's all this?
向您上贡 船长
Tribute, sir.
噢
Ooh!
他夺走了我的一切
He took everything from me…
让我充满了愤怒
and filled me with rage.
和痛苦
And pain.
故事到这里就结束了
And here is where the tale ends.
还没有 船长 看那儿
Not yet, Capitán. There!
我就说会找到他
Found as promised.
就是说她有海图
So she's saying she's got the map,
也只有她能看得懂
but she's the only one who can follow it?
那 宰了她吗？
So we should shoot her?
你别动她 她能带我们找到三叉戟
Leave her be. She will take us to the Trident.
几个钟头前就这么说
You've been saying that for hours.
有两件事她在蒙我们 嗯？
Two things we know are true, eh?
- 嗯 - 大白天根本看不到星星
- Yes. - Stars don't shine by day.
还有呢 她根本不懂蚊子
And she forgot the donkey.
我们怎么去找一片任何地图都没有标记出的陆地？
How can we go to a spot where no land exists on any map?
这块航海钟和伦敦时间完全一致
This chronometer keeps the exact time in London.
我用它测算地平纬度进而确定经度
I'm using it to make an altitude measurement to determine longitude.
这样才能知道 我们在海上的精确位置
Only then will we find our exact spot at sea.
你凭一块表就能找到三叉戟？
So you expect to find the Trident with a timepiece?
是的
Yes.
我的计算方法非常地精准
My calculations are precise and true.
我不仅研究天文 我还懂计时学
I'm not only an astronomer, I'm also a horologist.
嗯
Mmm.
没什么好丢人的
No shame in that, dear.
总得赚点钱 养活自己 对吧？
I mean, we all have to earn a living, eh?
对
Oh, yeah.
不 我说的不是妓女的「妓」
No. No, I'm a horologist.
我妈跟你同行
So was my mum.
但她不会像你一样当众说出来
But she didn't crow about it as loud as you.
这么说 你妈妈也喜欢研究这个？
Are you saying your mother was academically inclined?
多数时候呢 只能是躺着… 研究
More like, horizontally reclined.
计时学 关注的是时间
Horology is the study of time.
说对了 我妈总是要看表
And she was always looking at her watch.
这个我能作证
I can vouch for that.
所以只有你能找到那个地方 对吗？
So no one can find the "X" but you, right?
- 不是 - 那蚊子呢？
- No. - And the donkey?
后边有船
Ship to the aft!
萨拉查
Salazar.
杰克 死人不报仇的话 是不会安息的
Jack, the dead will not rest until they get their revenge.
死人？
Dead?
呃 不不不 你可没说有死人的事儿
No, no. The dead were never part of this deal.
我们就不应该跟着倒霉船长还有女巫出海
We should have never followed a luckless pirate and a witch to sea.
那就这样 杀了他们
Right, that's it. Kill 'em all.
杀了我？那 那 那我就死了
Kill me and I'll be dead.
那那些死人就… 就没办法找我报仇了
And then the other dead won't be able to have their revenge…
我死都死了
against me.
对吧？
Being dead.
- 什么？- 那样只会激怒他们 他说得对
- What? - Which will anger them even more. He's right.
没错
That's right.
你们海盗都这么蠢吗？
Are all pirates this stupid?
- 是的 - 是啊 是啊
- Yes. - Yeah. Yeah.
那我们该怎么办？
What are we going to do?
作为船长 我倒是有一个提议…
As Captain, might I suggest…
叛变？你就只能想到这个？
Mutiny? You had to suggest a mutiny?
卡琳娜 死人追上来了
Carina, the dead are coming.
噢 我是不会相信的 都是超自然的胡扯
Well, I choose not to believe in supernatural nonsense.
你没看到后面的船吗？
Do you not see what's behind us?
放出去 把它们放出去
Drop them. Drop them.
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
你们说的死人要找杰克 而杰克在这条船上
The men on that ship are looking for Jack and Jack is on this boat.
所以我要弃船逃命
So I'm going to swim for it.
居然这样？我要是你的话我也会这样做
How dare you do exactly what I would do if I were you.
- 卡琳娜 快停下 - 不不不… 千万不要停
- Carina, stop that. - No, no, no. Don't stop that.
你这样做太过份了
This has gone far enough.
哪儿过份了
No, it has not.
别听他的 继续 继续
Listen not to him. Carry on. Carry on.
你瞧你？就剩最后一件了
Why? She was almost finished.
我看到她的腿了
I saw her ankles.
你小子要是闭嘴还能看到更多的呢
You'd have seen a lot more if you'd have kept your cake hole shut.
去吃了小麻雀
Kill the Sparrow.
情况不太妙啊
Oh, that's not good, is it?
赶紧划小子 快点 再快点儿
Keep rowing, man. Faster. Faster.
不 我不干了
No. That's it.
我要去找她
I'm going with her.
你要抛弃我 去找那个穿短衬裤的计时女？
You would leave me for some horologist in her knickers?
是的
Yes.
你们男人都一样
You men are all alike.
鲨鱼？
Shark.
亨利
Henry!
这样没什么用啊
Doesn't seem to be working!
谁说没用 没事的
No, we'll be fine. We'll be fine.
冲啊
Vamos!
他们怎么做到的？
How do they do that?
我们得游到岸上 我把鲨鱼引开
We have to swim for it. I'll distract them.
快跳
Now!
走开
Oh, shoo!
Go away!
亨利
Henry!
噢
Oh!
嗨 杰克·斯派罗
Hi, Jack Sparrow.
杰克小麻雀
Jack the Sparrow.
西班牙人？
You're Spanish?
鬼 鬼 有鬼
You're ghosts!
哦 原来他们不能上岸
Oh. They're unable to step on land.
意料之中
I knew that, though.
走开
Ghosts!
卡琳娜
Carina!
你欠我的马上就该还了
You will soon pay for what you did to me.
不 不… 不 不必算那么清楚
No, no, no. There's no need to bother, really.
- 卡琳娜 - 我这会儿没空闲聊
- Carina! - I have no time to chat…
我的海图刚刚跑了
because me map's just run away.
那我们就在这儿 等你
I will be waiting for you!
你等我干什么？哪个孙子要你等我
Why would you be waiting for me? Why would he be waiting for me?
发现海盗
Pirates!
（垂死海鸥号）
斯克拉姆
Scrum.
船长
Captain.
杰克总跟我说 要是他出了意外
Jack always told me that if anything should ever happen to him…
他希望你来当船长
he wanted you to be captain.
可是他们都支持您 而且您还戴着船长帽呢
Yeah, but the men voted for you. That's why you got a captain's hat.
不管怎么说
Be that as it may…
那是杰克的遗愿 所以要好好干 接他的班
them were his wishes, so be a good lad and take the wheel.
给
And, uh, you…
戴好船长帽
take the captain's hat.
噢
Oh.
真不知道怎么感谢…
This is the proudest moment of my…
再不说出杰克的去向
We will beat your captain to death…
你们的船长就要被打死了
until he reveals where they're heading.
卡琳娜
Carina!
啊小伙子 我知道你在苦恼什么
I know what's ailing you, boy.
你的内心正受着煎熬
You've got the unscratchable itch.
听着 只有跟着卡琳娜 才能找到三叉戟
Carina is the only one who can help us find the Trident…
我没有爱上她
and I'm not in love with her.
爱？谁说你爱上她了？你自己说的？
Love? Who said anything about love? What are you talking about?
那你说我内心煎熬？
The unscratchable itch?
疥疮 我说的是疥疮
Scabies. I'm talking about scabies.
小虫子在皮肤底下钻来钻去
Small mites that burrow under the skin.
好多年了 真是太难熬了
It's certainly ailing me, has been for years.
噢 不
Oh, no.
（刽子手湾 不欢迎陌生人）
救命啊
Help!
救救我
Help me!
- 救命啊 - 卡琳娜
- Carina! - Help!
- 亨利 快救我 - 快救啊
- Henry, help me! - Help her!
我现在下令 你们全都给我去死
By rule of the King, I sentence you all to death!
我觉得呀 咱俩该互相坦白一下藏宝贝的地方
I think we should tell each other where our treasures are buried…
说不定咱俩谁能活下来
just in case one of us survives.
哦 有道理
Oh, good idea.
那你先说
You go first.
我的宝贝埋在阿鲁巴岛两裸棕榈树之间的野坟里
My treasure is buried between two crossed palm trees in an unmarked grave in Aruba.
你的呢？
What about yours?
我没有宝贝
I haven't got any.
你说过能让我杀了杰克
You promised me Jack's blood!
但是他被困住了
But Jack be trapped!
他休想离开那座岛了
He can never escape that island.
可他上了岸
He's on land!
你好
Hello.
我遵守了协定 我可以带我的人上岸去
I upheld our deal. Me men and meself will go ashore.
把杰克给你抓回来
The scurvy traitor will be yours…
以我的荣誉担保
on me honour.
荣誉？什么荣誉 伙计？什么荣誉？
Honour? What honour, hombre? What honour?
你根本不懂得荣誉
You don't know what honour is.
你先饶了我一命 我去把杰克给你抓回来
Spare me my life, and I'll fetch you the Sparrow.
你看怎么样？
An accord?
醒醒 斯派罗
Wake up, Sparrow.
醒醒 斯派罗 你欠的债该还了
Wake up, Sparrow. It's time to pay your debt.
猪头… 猪头凯利？
Pig… Pig Kelly?
老朋友啊
Me old mates.
老朋友？你们听到了吗？
Mates? You hear that, boys?
这个满嘴瞎话的家伙欠了我一大笔钱
This lyin' pirate owes me a plunder of silver…
今天居然跑到刽子手湾
and luck has brought him to Hangman's Bay…
自己送上门来了 那好 还钱吧
where he can settle his debt here and now.
哦 呃 这个 那什么我会 我会还的
Oh, and I will. I will, Pig.
怎么还你说
Name your price.
给你个老婆 比阿特丽斯
Her name is Beatrice…
我可怜的妹妹 守寡多年了
and she's my poor, widowed sister.
这算什么啊？
What is that?
她本来想找个体面的男人
She's been looking for a respectable man.
不过你也凑合
But you'll have to do.
赶紧开始吧 老哥
Louis, let's get on with this.
不 不 为什么我要…
No! Why? Why would we do that?
你要让她活得体面些
To make an honest woman of her, Jack.
恭喜你 杰克 今天结婚了
Congratulations. It's your wedding day.
那我们开始吧
Let us begin.
我们可以去谷仓里度蜜月
We'll honeymoon in the barn.
不不不不
No, no, no.
听我说猪头
Now, Pig, how could I…
我不能昧着良心娶她
honestly make an honest woman out of it?
我也没办法让她这样的女人活得体面
That… Her. I mean, her.
这一群又是什么？
What are those things?
我们的孩子
Our children.
你最好别看他们的眼睛
Best not look them in the eye.
现在有请伴郎和伴娘
Bring the best man and the bridesmaid.
我看到他的眼睛了
I looked it in the eye.
请把你的手放到《圣经》上
Place your hand on the Bible.
啊 那个 那个 我有疥疮
I've got scabies.
- 我也有 - 啊
- So do I. - Ugh!
把你的手放到《圣经》上
Place your hand on the Bible.
我现在还尿床呢
I'm a bed-wetter.
说「你愿意」
Say "I do".
不然我一枪打爆你的头
Or I'll put a bullet in your skull.
杰克 你不说我们都得死
Jack, they're going to kill us!
- 谁管你啊 - 赶紧说你愿意
- I don't care! - Just say "I do."
- 最后一次机会 - 等等
- Last chance, Jack. - Wait!
这样肯定 呃 肯定不合法
Surely, this is not legal.
的确不合法
This is not legal.
他说得对
He's right.
有人愿意站出来 反对这桩婚姻吗？
Does any man here object to these nuptials?
- 我愿意 - 祝贺你们
- I do. - Congratulations!
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride!
天呐
No.
你 你 你… 你爱吃海鲜 是吧？
You… You like seafood, do you?
来呀
Come on!
杰克 我们又见面了
Jack, we meet again.
巴波萨
Hector!
他真是我全世界最好的朋友
This is me bestest mate in the whole world.
我就知道你迟早要安定下来的
I always knew you'd settle down eventually.
你带礼物来了吗？
Did you bring me a gift?
这个算吧
That'll do.
你气色不错 走路可真有劲儿
You look marvellous. Got quite the spring in your step.
断腿长出来了？
Has your leg grown back?
呃 船长 我们该回去找萨拉查
Uh, Captain, shouldn't we be getting back to Salazar…
用斯派罗的命换我们自己的啦？
trade Mr Sparrow's life in for our own?
是该那样了
Aye, that we could…
不过我是来找三叉戟的
but I've come for the Trident of Poseidon.
你要骗那个死人船长？
You're gonna double-cross the dead?
你向他保证了的
You did promise.
拿到了三叉戟 我就能重新掌控大海
And with it, I'll gut the dead that stole my command of the sea.
听起来是个不错的计划
As much as I love this plan…
但是没有船快得过那艘破烂的鬼船
no vessel can outrun that wretched hull of a ship.
还真有 杰克
But there be one, Jack.
我知道最快的船 黑珍珠号
The fastest ship I know, the Pearl…
五年前被黑胡子封印在了一个玻璃瓶子里
trapped in that bottle by Blackbeard five winters ago.
凭借黑胡子那老东西的宝剑之力
By the power of that blackguard's sovereign blade…
我现在要释放黑珍珠号 让它重现昔日的荣光
I hereby release the Black Pearl to her former and rightful glory.
做好准备
Get ready!
大家做好准备啊
Get ready for it!
要来了
It's coming!
要来了 要来了 要来了 来啦
It's coming! It's coming, it's coming!
大家退后 都退后 它…
Stand aside! Stand aside!
它回来了
It's coming!
它缩小了？
It's shrunken.
它怎么会变这么小？
Why doesn't it unshrink?
估计是太冷了？
Maybe it's cold, huh?
船应该在海里
She needs the sea.
多好的一艘船呐
She was a fine ship.
让…
Let…
一艘船只能有一个船长
There be room for only one captain.
噢 嗯 讨厌的小畜生
Ooh! Filthy beast.
该和死人赛一场了
Time to race the dead.
待在岸上才安全
The only safe place is the land.
我们干嘛要离开陆地呢？你说是吧？
Why are we going away from the land? Anyone?
船长 你的海图不够完善
Captain, your map is incomplete.
我可以带你们去找三叉戟 只要你信我
I can take us to the Trident if you'd only trust me.
你说是吧？
Anyone?
你到底有没有在听我说话呀？
Did you not hear anything I just said?
凭几颗星星 你说就能看出一幅海图来？
So you be saying that that star is pretendin' to be a map?
船长 所有的地图上都没有标出这个女人所说的岛
Sir, there is no island on any map to support what the woman says.
船长 你明白不了她说的含义
Captain, you don't have to understand her.
相信她就是了
Just believe her.
有人吗？
Anyone?
要是有个什么尖东西 我能把锁撬开
If we had something sharp, I could pick that lock.
这鬼地方哪有什么尖东西？
You're not gonna find anything sharp in here.
别再乱动了 烦死个人
Keep still, you bilge rat.
船长
Captain!
我再也不想当船长了
No, please! I don't wanna be captain any more!
放了他们
Release 'em!
船长 你不会是要让
Sir, you wouldn't allow…
一个女人来掌舵吧？
a woman to steer your ship?
让她看着星星导航 不然我们就都得死
She will follow her star, or we'll all die together.
黑珍珠号 它又起航了
The Black Pearl! She sails again!
快点儿划
Come on, lads!
这艘船 那些鬼魂…
This ship, those ghosts…
逻辑上有点儿说不通啊
There can be no logical explanation.
那些海上的传说是真的 卡琳娜
The myths of the sea are real, Carina.
你总算知道自己是错的了
I'm glad you can finally see you were wrong.
错的？
Wrong?
我只是有点疑惑
Perhaps I had some doubts.
我从没见过这样跟别人道歉的
This is the worst apology I've ever heard.
道歉？我 我为什么要道歉？
Apology? Why would I apologise?
因为我们被死人追杀
Because we've been chased by the dead,
然后开着从瓶子里拿出来的船
sailing on a ship raised from a bottle.
你倒是解释一下啊
Where is your science in that?
好吧 我向你道歉
Fine, then I will apologise.
接着说
Go on, then.
我觉得你也应该向我道歉才是
Although one could argue that you owe me an apology…
因为你害得我差点被那些坏蛋杀了
as my life has been threatened by pirates and dead men.
所以你现在相信了 真是抱歉
Which you now believe in, sorry to say.
那就原谅你吧
Apology accepted.
我去瞭望台了
I'm going to the lookout.
谢谢你理解我
I'm glad you see it my way.
向左十二度
Twelve degrees to port!
- 枪炮准备 - 遵命
- Ready the guns. - Aye!
枪炮准备
Ready the guns!
那些海盗要去找三叉戟
Those pirates are going for the Trident.
这是你从哪儿得来的 小姑娘？
Where did you get that from, missy?
我知道这本书
I know this book.
多年前 它被人从一艘意大利船上偷走了
Stolen from an Italian ship many years ago.
被偷走？不 你搞错了
Stolen? No, you're mistaken.
我印象很深刻 封皮上应该有一颗红宝石
There was a ruby on the cover I would not soon forget.
这是我父亲留给我的
This was given to me by my father…
显然 他是个科学家…
who was clearly a man of science.
显然 他是个偷东西的贼
He was clearly a common thief.
我决不会允许一个海盗 玷污我父亲的名誉
The memory of my father will not be defiled by the tongue of a pirate.
这日记我生来就有
This diary is my birthright.
父亲把它和我一起留在孤儿院门口
Left to me on the steps of a children's home.
上面写着我的名字
Along with a name and nothing else.
哦 这么说你是孤儿？
Oh, so you're an orphan.
那你叫什么？
What be you called?
和北方最亮的星座同一个名字
Brightest star in the North gave me my name.
那应该就是卡琳娜
That would be Carina.
卡琳娜·史密斯
Carina Smyth.
你还懂点天文
So you do know your stars.
我是个船长
I'm a captain.
我知道哪颗星星能带我返航
I know which stars to follow home.
史密斯
Smyth.
史密斯是个多么特别的姓氏啊
Smyth is quite an unusual name.
我们以前是不是认识那谁
Did we not once…
也姓史密斯？
know someone called Smyth?
闭上你的嘴
Shut your trap.
不过名字呢？
What was her name?
到了舌尖上说不出来了 噢
It's right on the tip of me tongue. Oh!
你还想不想要舌头？
Do you wanna lose that tongue?
玛格丽特·史密斯
Margaret Smyth.
是啊
Aye.
要不然我们做笔交易？
Should we make an accord then?
或者我也可以去告诉某人
Or shall I tell you-know-who.
你我都心知肚明的事？
what we both know to be true?
这件事你我到死都不能说出来
We both take this secret to our graves.
这么说是真的？我只是试探一下
You mean, it is true? I was bluffing.
我可不是
I'm not.
我要是死了 你拿什么跟死人船长谈条件？
You kill me, you got nothing to bargain the dead with.
所以你得让我活着
So you need me.
我不得不说 巴波萨
I'll have to be frank, Hector.
你长得可真不是一般的丑
You are very, very ugly.
你怎么就能生出这么个漂亮俊俏的女儿呢？
So how could you produce a fetching creature such as that?
她妈妈死了
Margaret died.
我这当爸爸的虽然混蛋 可我也盼着女儿好
I summoned as much honour as a worthless blaggard ever could.
我把她送到了孤儿院之后
I placed the infant in an orphanage…
再没有去看她
never to see her again.
我留下个红宝石 以为她能过得好一点儿
I thought the ruby might afford her some ease in life…
没想到她会去研究日记本里的东西
but I never imagined she'd take those scribblings…
还当成了人生志向
and make a life of her own.
结果又找回到我这里
A life that's led her back to me.
看起来现在的情况 对我好像非常有利啊 老爸
I'd say this puts me in a rather favourable position, Daddy.
要什么你说
You tell me what you want.
我要我的罗盘
I want me compass.
还要216大桶上好的朗姆酒
216 barrels of rum.
还有这猴子
And the monkey.
你想养它？
You want Jack?
吃它 我要吃掉它 我要吃了这猴…
Dinner. I want to eat him, I want to eat that monkey…
醒醒吧 杰克
No deal, Jack.
那么聪明的一个姑娘
A clever young woman such as that would never believe…
是绝对不会相信 我这样的人会是她的老爸
that a swine like me could ever be her blood.
三叉戟 我一定能得到
And the Trident will be mine.
海军
Redcoats!
是海军
准备开炮
Prepare to fire!
- 准备开炮 - 准备开炮
- Prepare to fire! - Prepare to fire!
拿起武器
Man that gun!
敌军在右舷方向
She comes starboard.
我们要战斗到底
We shall fight to the last.
黑珍珠号绝不能再次被人夺走
The Pearl will not be taken from me again.
长官
Sir.
海上的控制权只能属于大英帝国
Only the British Empire will hold to the power of the sea.
不论发生什么 你只管开船
Whatever happens, stay your course.
杰克·斯派罗
Jack Sparrow!
杰克·斯派罗 我来找你讨债了
Jack Sparrow. I've come with a butcher's bill.
巴波萨呢？
Where is he?
保护好自己 伙计们 跟他们拼了
Defend yourselves, men. To the death!
能不能快点儿 你是拿黄油磨的刀吗？
Hurry up, man. What did you sharpen it with? Butter?
看你还往哪儿躲
There's nowhere to hide.
壮起胆子 保卫黑珍珠 呀
Let's be brave. Save the Pearl!
就是这里了
This has to be it.
应该就是这里了
It has to be here.
快找到那片陆地
Find that land.
不然我们都得死
Or we'll all die.
我们快到了
We're nearly there!
它 它就在附近
It's here somewhere.
哇…
Whoa…
找到你要找的地方没有？
Have you found what you're looking for yet, miss?
我正在找
I'm trying!
星星就要看不见了
The stars will soon be gone.
哇 哇
Whoa! Whoa!
卡琳娜
Carina!
亨利 快看
Henry, look!
就是那座岛
The island is there.
你找到了
You found it!
那座岛
The island.
陆地
Land.
快回玛丽号
Get to the Mary!
卡琳娜
Carina!
亨利
Henry!
亨利被抓走了
They took Henry!
现在只有三叉戟能救他了
The Trident be all that can save him now.
我们一定要找到三叉戟
Then we have to find it.
三叉戟在哪儿？
Where is it?
它肯定在这儿
It has to be here.
你来看 杰克
Look at it, Jack.
我从没见过这么美丽的景象
It's the most beautiful thing I've ever seen.
这就是我父亲希望我找到的东西
This is what my father wanted me to find.
礁石？
The rocks?
不 不是礁石
No, not rocks.
是星星
Stars.
这就是「无人能懂的海图」
This is The Map No Man Can Read.
这座海岛 完全就是星空的倒影
This island is a perfect reflection of the heavens.
那儿缺了一颗星星
One star's missing.
快来
Quickly!
我们必须找到三叉戟 去救亨利
We have to find the Trident to save Henry.
巴波萨 有件事得告诉你
Hector, I think you should know,
她是个计时女
she's a horologist.
为什么不亮了？
Why isn't it glowing?
放回去吧 卡琳娜
Finish it, Carina.
缺失的星星
The missing star.
为了我父亲
For my father.
对
Aye.
为你父亲
Do it for him.
你看
Look.
海神波塞冬之墓
Poseidon's tomb.
这边来
This way.
船长 您知道这很危险
Capitán, you know the danger.
别这么做
Don't do it.
没别的办法了
He has no choice.
杰克在陆地就要得到三叉戟了
Jack is on land going for the Trident.
我们一定有别的办法
Capitán, there must be another way.
一旦您附身活人就再也回不来了
Once you possess the living, there's no coming back.
您会困在他的身体里出不来
You will be trapped in his body forever.
三叉戟能让我恢复
The Trident will set me free.
那只麻雀的死期到了
Time to kill a Sparrow.
不
No!
看 杰克 它在那儿
Look, Jack. There it is.
三叉戟
The Trident.
- 杰克 - 啊？
- Jack! - Huh?
嗯？
Huh?
你伤我 就是伤那小子 杰克
You cut me, you cut the boy, Jack.
亨利
Henry!
你好 斯派罗
Hola, Sparrow.
不好
Oh, no.
我恨你 斯派罗 去死吧 斯派罗
I hate the Sparrow. Die, Sparrow.
亨利
Henry!
他到陆地上来了 快醒醒
He's walking on land. Please.
亨利 快醒醒
Henry, wake up.
噢 快滚开
Oh, piss off!
哇哦
Whoa!
亨利快醒醒 杰克要被他杀了
Henry, wake up. He's killing Jack.
亨利
Henry!
海之神力
Power of the sea.
什么？
What?
释放海之神力
The power of the sea.
要释放海之神力
"To release the power of the sea…
则将一切分离
"all must divide."
既然三叉戟蕴含一切力量
If the Trident holds all the power, then…
那也包括诅咒的力量
Then every curse is held inside.
我以前就跟你说过
As I told you before…
你现在向我投降 我就饶你…
surrender to me now and I'll let you…
一命
live.
你想要我投降吗？
You want me to surrender?
算是吧
Maybe.
你的传说结束了
This is where the tale ends.
不
No!
嘘
Shh.
分离
Divide.
亨利
Henry!
分离 断开
Divide. Break.
打断三叉戟就能
Break the Trident and you'll…
打破所有的诅咒
Break every curse at sea.
诅咒全都解除了
All curses are broken.
我们都活过来了
We are flesh and blood!
黑珍珠号
The Pearl!
我的船
My Pearl!
快上去
Climb!
爬上来 快
Move! Fast!
千万要稳住伙计们
Hold it steady, boys!
别让它滑了
Don't let her slip!
杰克
Jack!
跳
Jump!
快点儿
Faster!
快点儿 起锚
Up! Anchor!
快把锚拉起来 快
Get the anchor up! Quick!
停 停 快拉起来 拉起来
Stop! Stop! Bring it up!
反着推 快拉起来 快点儿
Bring it up! Bring it up! Come on!
快拉上来
Bring it up!
船长 船长
Capitán! Capitán!
噢 断了
Oh, crumbs!
哇 哇
Whoa. Whoa.
噢
Oh!
我抓住你了
I've got you!
用力推
Stronger.
我是你的什么？
Who am I to you?
我的宝贝
Treasure.
抓紧
Hold on!
巴波萨
Hector!
稳住右舷
Hold her starboard!
海盗的命啊 巴波萨
Pirate's life, Hector.
你没事吧？
You all right?
我不知道
I don't know.
一瞬间我感觉拥有了一切
For a moment, I had everything, Henry.
现在又什么都没了
Now, it's all gone again.
不是都没了 史密斯小姐
It's not all gone, Ms Smyth.
巴波萨
Barbossa.
我的姓是巴波萨
My name is Barbossa.
也许杰克说对了
Maybe Jack was right.
说对了什么？
About what?
我内心深处的煎熬
The unscratchable itch.
你为什么打我？
What did you do that for?
我想看看是不是真的你
Just checking it's truly you.
我怕你是鬼附身
That you're not still a ghost.
是我
It's me.
嗯 那就算我…
Then I was…
错了
Wrong.
一个小失误 虽然 这个…
Slightly in error. Although…
我现在原谅你了
Apology accepted.
荷兰人号
The Dutchman.
亨利
Henry.
嗨 爸爸
Yes, Father.
让我看看你
Let me look at you, son.
你怎么做到的？
How did you do it?
你怎么打破诅咒的？
How did you break the curse?
我给你讲一个传说
Let me tell you a tale.
关于人世间最珍贵的宝藏
A tale of the greatest treasure known to man.
那我一定要听听
That's a tale I wanna hear.
恶心得叫人饭都吃不下了
What a truly revolting sight.
让开道
Make way!
杰克船长过甲板了
Captain Jack Sparrow on deck!
说得好
Indeed!
欢迎回来 船长
Welcome back, Captain.
哦 谢谢你 让一让
Oh, thank you very much. Coming through.
船长
Captain!
谢谢
Thank you.
我会记住你的
I remember you.
- 欢迎你 船长 - 谢谢
- Sirs. - Thank you.
太好了 吉布斯总管
Oh, good. Master Gibbs.
还是你来掌舵 船长
The ship is yours, Captain.
谢谢
Ah, thank you.
猴子
Monkey.
谢谢了
Thank you.
接下来去哪儿 船长？
What be our heading, Captain?
我们用星星导航 吉布斯总管
We shall follow the stars, Master Gibbs.
好 好 船长
Aye, aye, Captain!
我要去最爱的天边 赴一个约会
I have a rendezvous beyond my beloved horizon.